Finding Aid for the David P. Gamble papers LSC.1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Photography, 1920-2007
  - Subseries 6.2: Photo clippings, undated
    - Picture files: news photo clippings (3 of 4), undated (Box 12)
    - Picture files: news photo clippings (4 of 4), undated (Box 13)
- Series 7: Fula research materials, 1920-2007
  This series is comprised of material related to Gamble's study of Fula language and culture. It includes original field notes and bibliographies, Fula educational lesson books, and secondary articles related to the Fula language, as well as Fula grammars, dictionaries, and translations. Working drafts of Gamble's own Fula-English dictionary are included. There is some material related to Fula as an ethnic group. Series materials are in English, French, and Fula.
  This series has not been processed.
  - Fula language and grammar, 1950s-1980s (Box 44)
    Several folders of original DG field notes & bibliographies, Fula educational lesson books, some secondary articles related mostly to the Fula language, Fula grammar, Fula dictionaries, and translations. Some materials related to Fula as ethnic group. Materials in English, French, and Fula.
  - Books and research materials, undated (Box 45)
    Books and index cards.
- Series 8: Lebu, Serer, Jola, and Serahuli research materials, 1920-2007
  This series is comprised of original field notes, bibliographies, census data, and linguistic documentation, as well as secondary sources related to Gamble's study among Jola, Lebu, Serer, and Serahuli ethnic communities in The Gambia.
  - Serahuli: general: offprints and extracts, notes on early sources (1 of 2), 1980s (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - Serahuli: general: offprints and extracts, notes on early sources (2 of 2), 1980s (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - Serahuli: census, 1953-1954 (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Serahuli: field notes, circa 1953 (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Serahuli: bibliography, circa 1966 (Box 85, Folder 19)
  - Lebu and Serer research materials, undated (Box 36)
  - Jola research material, undated (Box 37)
- Series 9: Sierra Leone/Temne research materials
  This series is comprised of materials related to Gamble's research in and about Sierra Leone, and his work on a UNICEF project, "Develop Sierra Leone." It includes original field notes, questionnaires, and correspondence, as well as offprints and other secondary material related to Temne language and geography. The series also consists of photographic prints and negatives taken in Lunsar and other areas of Sierra Leone.
  - Research materials, may include photographs (1 of 4), undated (Box 50)
  - Research materials, may include photographs (2 of 4), undated (Box 51)
  - Research materials, may include photographs (3 of 4), undated (Box 52)
  - Research materials, may include photographs (4 of 4), undated (Box 53)
  - Stories and folktales, may include "Brer rabbit", undated (Box 40)
- Series 10: Gambian Studies Series, 1976-2007
  This series is comprised of bound copies of Gamble's monumental 52-volume self-published book series, Gambian Studies. It includes bibliographies of The Gambia; dictionaries and grammars of Wolof, Mandinka, and Fula languages; collections of folktales, stories, and proverbs; studies of historical sources; and general ethnographies of the country's people.
  This series is arranged chronologically, by volume number.
  - Gambian Studies (Volumes 1-16), 1976-2007 (Box 61)
  - Gambian Studies (Volumes 17-28), 1976-2007 (Box 62)
  - Gambian Studies (Volumes 29-39), 1976-2007 (Box 63)
  - Gambian Studies (Volumes 40-52), 1976-2007 (Box 64)
- Series 11: Gambian newspapers and periodicals, circa 1960-2004
  This series is comprised of newspapers and periodicals published in The Gambia between 1960 and 2004. Publications include Daily Observer, Weekend Observer, Gambian News Bulletin, and West Africa, among others.
  - Daily Observer, 1993 (Box 68)
  - Daily Observer, 1997-1998 (Box 69)
  - Daily Observer and Weekend Observer, 1997 (Box 70)
  - Gambian News Bulletin (1 of 2), circa 1962-1987 (Box 4)
  - Gambian News Bulletin (2 of 2), circa 1962-1987 (Box 5)
  - Gambian News Bulletin and West Africa, circa 1962-1987 (Box 6)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (1 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 7)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (2 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 8)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (3 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 35)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (4 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 65)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (5 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 66)
  - Gambian newspapers, various (6 of 6), circa 1960-2004 (Box 67)
  - Weekend Observer, 1996-1997 (Box 71)
- Series 12: Books and Theses, 1920-2007
  This series is divided into two subseries: the first is comprised of theses collected by Gamble in the course of his research and the second consists of miscellaneous books not originally associated with other series.
  - Subseries 12.1: Theses, 1967-1994
    - Theses (1 of 3), 1967-1994 (Box 1)
    - Theses (2 of 3), 1967-1994 (Box 2)
    - Theses (3 of 3), 1967-1994 (Box 3)
  - Subseries 12.2: Books, 1920-2007
    - African research and documentation, undated (Box 56)
    - Early histories (1 of 2), undated (Box 42)
    - Early histories (2 of 2), undated (Box 43)
    - Gambia and natural sciences, undated (Box 55)
    - Gambian authors; Temne, French, and English sources, undated (Box 58)
    - Gen African history, Goree, Wolof, undated (Box 57)
    - Language and culture, undated (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous books, undated (Box 60)
    - Senegal, oral traditions, undated (Box 59)
    - Wolof, Mandinka, personal copies of books authored by Gamble, undated (Box 25)